welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
working with multiple videos on multiple
在多个上处理多个视频
video tracks and showing kind of the
视频曲目和显示的一种
priority and which video will get played
优先级以及将播放的视频
on top of another video so basically
在另一个视频的顶部 所以基本上
we're gonna be playing multiple videos
我们将播放多个视频
yeah I'll show you how that's done so I
好的 我会告诉你怎么做的 所以我
grabbed some video footage from
抓取了一些视频片段
pixabay.com these are videos you can
这些都是视频 你可以
hover over and kind of see it if we
悬停在上面 有点像是看到了我们
click on them we can just go it download
点击它们 我们可以直接去下载
so this is like I think it's one of the
所以这就像是我认为它是
clips I did this actually has some audio
剪辑我做的这个实际上有一些音频
with it and then I'm gonna drag these in
用它 然后我会把这些拖进来
so I have three video clips there in my
所以我的电脑里有三个视频片段
downloads folder I'm just going to drag
下载文件夹 我只是要拖动
them into my projects folder I'm left
放到我的项目文件夹里 我被留下了
clicking and dragging these in and then
点击并将其拖入 然后
we can watch them in our projects we can
我们可以在我们的项目中观看他们
just like to see what the video looks
只是想看看视频是什么样子的
like so this Mercedes ones actually
像这样 这辆梅赛德斯实际上是
already been edited and cut together
已经被编辑和剪辑在一起了
it's a bunch of different Clips that's
这是一堆不同的片段
been edited sometimes some of them are
有时被编辑过 其中一些是
even like slowed down they adjusted the
即使放慢了速度 他们也调整了
speed of it like I think right here it
它的速度就像我在这里想的那样
drives through some water maybe like
开车穿过一些水 可能是这样的
slow motion and so but what I want to do
慢动作等等 但我想做的是
which one has the audio I think it's
哪一台有我认为的音频
this one Edison has audio so we can see
这个爱迪生有音频 所以我们可以看到
a little blue audio line right at the
一条蓝色的音频线就在
bottom it shows two audio waves I'm
底部显示了两个音波 我
gonna left click and drag this down to
左键点击并将其向下拖动至
our video one because I want this to
我们的视频是因为我想让它
kind of be the base the base of our
有点像是基础 我们的基础
video like the constant so this video is
视频喜欢常量 所以这个视频是
gonna play the whole time in the
我会在比赛中全程上场
background of our video and it's also
我们视频的背景 它也是
gonna be playing this audio of like cars
会播放这段类似于汽车的音频
driving since the other two videos don't
开车 因为其他两个视频没有
have any audio with them so then I'm
与他们有任何音频 所以我就
just gonna drag and drop onto video
只需拖放到视频上
track to will drag this one here of the
Track to将把这一个拖到这里
freeway and onto track three that's one
上高速公路 上三号轨道 这就是一条
of the Mercedes so if you see what
所以如果你看到了什么
happens we were watching this video that
碰巧我们在看这段视频
had the audio we're on our project
有我们正在做的项目的音频
monitor right now oh now we're on a
现在的监视器 哦 现在我们正在
project monitor so we were watching this
项目监控员 所以我们在看这个
video below but now we're seeing the
下面的视频 但现在我们看到
Mercedes if I left click and drag the
梅赛德斯如果我左键单击并拖动
Mercedes over here forward in time and
梅赛德斯在时间上向前推进
then unclick we see the video changes
然后取消单击我们看到视频更改
because the playhead is looking at this
因为播放头正在看着这个
video now so between these two the
现在视频就是在这两个人之间
playhead it's choosing to view whatever
PlayHead它选择观看任何
it is the topmost video so the higher
这是最上面的视频 所以越高
the number of the video
视频的编号
track the more the top the more priority
跟踪越多越重要
it has to get seen
它必须被人看到
but both videos are playing at the same
但这两个视频在同一时间播放
time so if we play this right now
时间到了 所以如果我们现在播放这个
we'll see or we'll hear the audio from
我们会看到 或者我们会听到来自
this lower video but we're seeing the
这段较低的视频 但我们看到
video from this top video that makes
这段顶级视频中的视频使
sense so if we drag this out of the way
所以如果我们把这件事拖到一边
and now we're seeing just this one video
现在我们看到的只是这一段视频
that has the audio with it so what we
它有音频 所以我们有什么
can do this is something I do a lot
做这件事是我经常做的事
actually I'll have one video playing
实际上 我要放一段视频
constantly especially if you have
不断地 尤其是如果你有
multiple camera angles of the same thing
同一事物的多个摄像角度
happening like an interview you have a
就像面试一样发生 你有一个
camera pointing at someone's face or I
摄像头对准某人的脸或我
can't a camera pointing at the
不能让摄像机对准
interviewer and then a camera pointing
采访者 然后是摄像机指向
at the interviewee I'll have one of the
在面试时 我会有一位
interviews playing that has the best
播放最好的采访
audio at the bottom and then I'll have
音频在底部 然后我就会有
I'll bring in other clips just short
我会把其他短片带进来
versions of it so we can grab this razor
它的不同版本 这样我们就可以拿到这把剃刀
tool and just cut out like a really
工具 然后就像一个真正的
short clip here then go to my selector
短片在这里 然后转到我的选择器
tool and know this drag it in here and
工具 并知道这一点 将它拖到这里并
maybe we can even drag in this little
或许我们甚至可以把这一点
piece that we had will have that be the
我们拥有的那一块将会是
start and we'll go to there and then
开始 我们会去那里 然后
it'll come in then maybe we'll have the
它会进来的 然后也许我们会有
Mercedes one start so what this will do
梅赛德斯一号发车 这会有什么效果？
is it's going to play I'll just click
它要播放了吗？我只需点击
and drag so it's going to play this
然后拖动它 这样它就会播放这个
video and then when I gets to this point
视频 然后当我谈到这一点
it's going to play the video underneath
它将在下面播放视频
and then it's going to play this video
然后它将播放这段视频
and it'll play the video underneath and
它会在下面播放视频
we'll play the Mercedes video while
我们将在播放梅赛德斯视频的同时
still playing the audio so we'll just
仍在播放音频 所以我们只需
click and actually just play it and
点击并实际播放即可
watch
观看
we'll see where the playhead is going
我们将看到播放头的去向
now it's playing this freeway video
现在它正在播放这段高速公路视频
because it's on video too now it's gonna
因为它现在也被录像了 它将
drop down and play on video track 1
下拉并在视频轨道1上播放
because there's nothing in video track 2
因为2号录像带里什么都没有
right now and it's gonna jump back up to
现在 它将跳回到
video track 2 and play whatever is in
视频曲目2和播放中的任何内容
there while still playing the audio in
在那里同时还在播放音频
the background
背景
so really it's playing this background
所以它实际上是在播放这个背景
video we just can't see it because it's
视频我们就是看不到 因为它是
being covered up by video 2 and so in
被视频2掩盖 诸如此类
the last video we learned about how to
我们学习的最后一段视频是关于如何
transform just so we can kind of drive
转型 这样我们就能像开车一样
this home no pun intended
这个家没有双关语的意思
let's go to crop and transform we'll
让我们来裁剪和变形 我们将
drag a transform into here and if we
将变换拖到此处 如果我们
change the size of this video then we
更改此视频的大小 然后我们
can actually see what's happening now we
我们可以真正看到现在发生的事情
see we've got this video playing down
看 我们已经把这段视频淡化了
below and also this video playing up
下面还有这段视频
here and we can drag and have it be
在这里 我们可以拖着它走
playing down here if we want so that's
如果我们想在这里玩 那就是
pretty cool huh and we can even do all
很酷吧 我们甚至可以做所有的事情
three of them if we want to we can drag
其中三个 如果我们愿意 我们可以拖拽
this one and I'm gonna resize this I
这个 我要调整这个的大小
think I talked about this in another
我想我在另一个地方谈到了这一点
tutorial but you might have forgot if
教程 但您可能忘记了
you go to the end of the video you can
你可以走到视频的最后
actually just click and resize the video
实际上只需点击并调整视频大小
as long as you're not trying to go past
只要你不想走过去
the extent of the video or further
视频的范围或更远
forward in the beginning of the video so
在视频开头转发 所以
at these video clips that we cut over
在我们剪下的这些视频片段中
here we can drag them and make them a
在这里 我们可以拖动它们 使它们成为
little bit longer as long as we don't go
只要我们不去 就再久一点
past the extents of that so in fact I'll
超出了这一范围 所以事实上我会
put this back where it was though I'm
把它放回原处 尽管我
gonna move this up top here and we're
把这个搬到上面 我们就是
gonna keep it the same length as this
会让它保持和这个一样的长度
Mercedes video but we'll apply a
梅赛德斯视频 但我们将应用
transform to it as well and we'll resize
也变换到它 我们将调整大小
it as well so now we've got all kinds of
所以现在我们有各种各样的
different video happening here we've got
不同的视频发生在这里 我们有
the Mercedes video I'll put it right
梅赛德斯的视频我会纠正的
there so now when we play this might
所以现在当我们演奏这首曲子的时候
take a little bit to play but now we see
需要一点时间来玩 但现在我们看到了
the first-person view of driving this
驾驶这辆车的第一人称观点
car we see the Mercedes driving through
我们看到奔驰车驶过
water and we see all these cars going
水 我们看到所有的汽车都在
here so that's kind of how do video and
这就是视频和
video or a picture-in-picture
视频或画中画
I'm gonna do it I'll do another tutorial
我会做的 我会再做一次教程
on that later showing how to do like
在后面的演示中展示了如何像
desktop tutorials where it has your face
桌面教程 其中有您的脸
in the bottom right hand corner and then
在右下角 然后
it'll have like your desktop screen and
它会有像你的桌面屏幕和
the for the rest of it but that's
剩下的部分 但那是
basically how you accomplish it is it's
基本上 你如何完成它是它的
playing all three videos on all three
在所有三个视频上播放所有三个视频
video tracks and I guess just to get
录像带和我想只是为了
here let's just add in some audio too so
让我们在这里也添加一些音频
I'll drag in this audio file then we can
我会把这个音频文件拖进来 然后我们就可以
really open I mean just fit okay and
真的很开放 我是说 只要合身就行了
then it'll put it down here so then we
然后它会把它放在这里 然后我们
really have a lot going on
真的有很多事情要做
we're playing audio from here we're
我们在这里播放音频 我们是
playing three sources of video and two
播放三个视频源和两个
of the video are resized to be on top of
调整视频的大小 使其位于
each other our music it's a little bit
彼此 我们的音乐 这是一点点
laggy because it's trying to do its rap
滞后是因为它正试图做它的说唱
is trying to read 3 3 720p videos and
正在尝试阅读3 3720p的视频和
also play the audio and also apply the
还可以播放音频 并将
transforms and all that so but when we
变形等等 但是当我们
render it out it'll look just completely
把它渲染出来 看起来就像是完全
normal and in fact I'll show you except
很正常 事实上我会告诉你除了
I do want to do this let's just take
我真的想这么做 我们就这样做吧
this opportunity to learn how to use
这是一个学习如何使用
this thing here whatever this blue area
这个东西 不管这个蓝色区域是什么
is whatever selected in this blue area
在这个蓝色区域中选择的是什么
is what will get played up here in the
是什么将被渲染在这里在这里
player first of all and it's also what
首先是玩家 这也是
we can we can render an export out so if
我们可以 我们可以提供出口 所以如果
I just want to do it let's just do a
我只想做这件事 让我们做一个
short portion here cuz I don't want to
一小部分在这里 因为我不想
take forever to render and then we click
渲染要花费很长时间 然后我们点击
up on render and then we just say
在渲染上 然后我们只需说
selective zone instead of full project
选择区域而不是完整项目
then it will only render that portion
那么它将只呈现该部分
that 10 seconds roughly is what it looks
这10秒大致就是它看起来的样子
like so and in fact I'm gonna make it
就像这样 事实上我会成功的
even shorter so that we don't wait let's
更短 这样我们就不用等了 让我们
make it a teeny tiny and let's go to
让它变得微不足道 让我们去
render will render a selective zone and
渲染将渲染一个选择区域 并
we'll save it to the desktop and we'll
我们会将其保存到桌面 然后我们将
call it a whoops
那就叫呼呼吧
we don't WebM though which we'll just
我们不会使用WebM 但我们只需要
call it something and then we'll make
叫它什么 然后我们就做
sure it's an mp4 so I like to you could
当然是MP4 所以我喜欢你可以
do WebM but mp4 is kind of this a good
做WebM 但MP4是一种很好的
standard for uploading to like Facebook
上传到喜欢Facebook的标准
or YouTube and I'll just pause the video
或者YouTube和我只是暂停视频
while we render this out
当我们把它呈现出来的时候
okay so that took about 40 seconds to
好的 所以这花了大约40秒
render actually 48 seconds exactly to
实际渲染时间为48秒 精确到
render and will minimize and we'll just
渲染并将最小化 我们只需
watch this that's the video pretty cool
看这个 这是个很酷的视频
stuff so that's just a little hopefully
所以这只是一个小小的希望
that kind of maybe cleared up some
这可能会让人清醒一些
things in your mind as far as how to use
你脑海中的东西 至于如何使用
these different tracks and then we can
这些不同的轨道 然后我们就可以
add in you know multiple audio and if
加上你知道的多个音频 如果
you want to add in another track we can
您想添加另一首曲目吗？我们可以
just right click and we can go insert
只需点击鼠标右键 我们就可以插入
track and we can add another audio track
音轨 我们可以添加另一首音轨
Oh can't wait
哦 等不及了
audio - oh yeah we'll add an audio track
音频-哦 是的 我们将添加一首音频曲目
insert above audio - and we'll call it
在音频上方插入-我们将其命名为
wet it'll make it audio track and we'll
弄湿它会变成音轨 我们会
call it audio three and add so now we
将其称为音频三 然后添加到现在我们
have audio three we can rearrange it
有音频三 我们可以重新安排
somehow oh yeah I think we click this
不知何故 哦 是的 我想我们点击这个
button here anyway this is what you can
不管怎么说 这是你能做的
rearrange these as well so appreciate
把这些也重新整理一下 所以很欣赏
you watching this video hopefully that
你看这个视频的时候希望
was informative catch on next one
在下一场比赛中提供了丰富的信息